{"tossups": [{"question": "A parameter that governs this process displays an \u201coctant degeneracy,\u201d with solutions either above or below 45 degrees. The degeneracy of that parameter is predicted to be resolvable by long baseline experiments, and the probability of one form of this process is proportional to the sine square of twice that parameter. This process can be treated approximately by using \u201ctribimaximal\u201d (try-by-max-im-al) or \u201cdemocratic\u201d forms of the matrix that governs it. The first evidence for this process came from a threefold discrepancy between experiments and a standard astronomical model proposed by John Bahcall. The Daya (\"DIE\"-uh) Bay experiment determined the value of \u201ctheta one three,\u201d which was the last unknown mixing angle that governs this process. This process is modeled by the PMNS matrix, and the discovery of this process at the Super-Kamiokande detector in 1998 proved that the particles involved had nonzero mass. For 10 points, name this process in which the three flavors of uncharged leptons transform into one another.", "answer": "neutrino oscillations [or neutrino mixing; accept \u201cantineutrino\u201d in place of \u201cneutrino\u201d for the previous two answers; prompt on \u201cflavor oscillations\u201d or \u201cflavor mixing\u201d]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>neutrino oscillations</u></b> [or <b><u>neutrino mixing</u></b>; accept <b><u>antineutrino\u201d</u></b> in place of \u201cneutrino\u201d for the previous two answers; prompt on <u>flavor oscillations</u> or <u>flavor mixing</u>]", "acceptable": ["neutrino oscillations", "neutrino oscillations", "neutrino mixing", "antineutrino\u201d"], "promptable": ["flavor oscillations", "flavor mixing"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Late in this novel, the women at a dinner party are asked whether they\u2019d rather be waitresses or porn stars during a discussion of the popularity of the film Deep Throat. This novel\u2019s narrator is invited to a dinner at Vincent\u2019s to talk about the \u201cshocks that befell . . . the loved ones\u201d of the protagonist's father. A character in this novel is outraged when a newspaper profile of her cow-raising business features a caption that references her past participation in the Miss America pageant. In this novel, the protagonist\u2019s daughter finally masters her stuttering after converting to Jainism while in hiding after bombing the local general store and post office to bring the Vietnam War home. The protagonist of this novel operates a glove factory in Newark, New Jersey. The frame narrative of this novel is a high school reunion attended by Nathan Zuckerman. For 10 points, name this Philip Roth novel about Swede Levov.", "answer": "American Pastoral", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>American Pastoral</u></b>", "acceptable": ["American Pastoral", "American Pastoral"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "George Pimentel proposed a model that expanded the concept of \u201chalf bonds\u201d to model bond orders of one-half in ions with this many atoms to explain hypervalency. The \u201c2-norbornyl cation\u201d experiences delocalization between this many atoms. A common demonstration of the SALC (\"S-A-L-C\") method shows that the linear form of an ion with this many atoms results in the ungerade orbitals splitting and the gerade (un-gay-RAH-duh) orbitals becoming nonbonding, while that ion\u2019s cyclic form results in two slightly antibonding orbitals. That aforementioned compound with this many atoms exists in a para form with one-half spin or an ortho form with higher spin. Carbocation rearrangements occur through an intermediate with this many atoms, which forms an electron-deficient bond also seen in boranes. A molecule with this many carbons is treated as having sp2 (\"S-P-two\") hybridization in the Walsh model, and experiences extremely strained banana bonds. For 10 points, how many atoms are in the most strained rings possible, such as in aziridines (uh-ZEER-eh-deenz) or epoxides.", "answer": "three", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>three</u></b>", "acceptable": ["three", "three"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man\u2019s vice president was investigated for his part-ownership of the Ramapo (RAM-uh-poh) Water Company, which held tracts of land in the Catskills, especially after the St. Valentine\u2019s Day blizzard, a period of historically cold weather during this man\u2019s term. This man\u2019s vice president resided in a building dubbed the \u201cCream White House\u201d for playing host to guests like this man\u2019s treasury secretary, Lyman Gage, the former president of the First National Bank of Chicago. This president passed the Newlands Resolution to appoint a five-member commission to recommend laws for Hawaii. He forced his secretary of war, Russell Alger, to resign amid allegations including the embalmed beef scandal. This man, who nearly went bankrupt while serving as governor of Ohio, enacted the Dingley Tariff during his first year in office to restore rates back to the 1890 tariff that he sponsored while a congressman. For 10 points, name this American president shot in Buffalo by Leon Czolgosz (SHAHL-gosh) in 1901.", "answer": "William McKinley", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>William McKinley</u></b>", "acceptable": ["William McKinley", "William McKinley"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A \u201creply\u201d to this poem notes that \u201cseveral people called about office hours\u201d and concludes \u201csee you later; love; floss; please turn off the telephone.\u201d When asked why this work should be considered a poem, its author noted that \u201cit\u2019s metrically absolutely regular,\u201d which is untrue, leading Marjorie Perloff to conclude that this poem\u2019s author mistakes \u201csight for sound.\u201d A response to this poem ends by exclaiming \u201cI wanted you here in the wards, where I am the doctor!\u201d That parody of this poem, which recalls how \u201cwe laughed at the hollyhocks together / and then I sprayed them with lye\u201d and how the speaker chopped down the addressee\u2019s house, is a set of variations on its author by Kenneth Koch. A theme of teasing sexuality is often attributed to the description of the subject as \u201cso sweet / and so cold\u201d in this poem, which functions as a note left in the kitchen. For 10 points, the speaker of what poem by William Carlos Williams asks its reader to forgive him for taking plums from the icebox?", "answer": "\u201cThis Is Just to Say\u201d", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cThis Is Just to Say\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cThis Is Just to Say\u201d", "\u201cThis Is Just to Say\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Shortly after this modern-day country\u2019s independence, one of its founding fathers issued a proclamation stating that \u201cwe have rendered to these true cannibals war for war, crime for crime, outrage for outrage\u201d before concluding that the \u201csecret of being invincible\u201d is to maintain the \u201cprecious concord\u201d of \u201chappy harmony amongst yourselves.\u201d That proclamation, titled \u201cLiberty or Death,\u201d was issued in this country that modern conservative Christians such as Pat Buchanan have claimed has made a \u201cpact with the devil\u201d based on foundational moment in its independence, a religious ceremony at Bois Ca\u00efman (bwah kay-mahn) presided over by Dutty Boukman. A 1938 book that was inspired by the author meeting historian Alfred Auguste Nemours places this country\u2019s independence movement in the context of the French Revolution. C. L. R. James\u2019s book The Black Jacobins is history of a revolution in, for 10 points, what modern-day country once led by Jean-Jacques Dessalines (des-uh-leen) and Toussaint Louverture?", "answer": "Haiti [or Republic of Haiti; or R\u00e9publique d\u2019Ha\u00efti; or Repiblik Ayiti]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Haiti</u></b> [or <b><u>Republic of Haiti</u></b>; or <b><u>R\u00e9publique d\u2019Ha\u00efti</u></b>; or <b><u>Repiblik Ayiti</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Haiti", "Haiti", "Republic of Haiti", "R\u00e9publique d\u2019Ha\u00efti", "Repiblik Ayiti"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A story by this author follows an expert horse-judger whose journeys take him to the Tartars, who cover his heels with horsehair to stop him from escaping, and to a gypsy camp, where he kills his lover Grusha. An essay on this author observes that \u201cthe lower [he] descends on the scale of created things the more obviously does his way of viewing things approach the mystical.\u201d A character created by this author dreams of a gigantic cat with the voice of her father-in-law after dying from eating mushrooms. This author of The Enchanted Wanderer is the subject of Walter Benjamin\u2019s essay \u201cThe Storyteller.\u201d In a story by this man, a woman is drowned along with a rival who stole her last pair of stockings after she and her lover Sergey are exiled to Siberia for murdering her husband with a candlestick. One of his stories follows a craftsman who delights the tsar by putting horseshoes on a mechanical flee. For 10 points, what Russian author\u2019s skaz stories include \u201cLefty,\u201d and \u201cLady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District\u201d?", "answer": "Nikolai Leskov [or Nikolai Semyonovich Leskov]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Nikolai <b><u>Leskov</u></b> [or <b><u>Nikolai Semyonovich Leskov</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Nikolai Leskov", "Leskov", "Nikolai Semyonovich Leskov"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A long-acting analogue of this compound self assembles into 24.4-nanometer-thick nanotubes and is named lanreotide (lan-REE-oh-tide), while the analogue pasireotide (puh-SEER-ee-oh-tide) serves as an orphan drug for Cushing\u2019s disease. An indium-111-marked analogue of this hormone is used in techniques graded by the Krenning score method of locating sarcoidosis (sar-koy-DOH-siss) and neuroendocrine tumors. A different analogue of this compound is bound to DOTA (\"D-O-T-A\") in a compound used for imaging tumors, and both of those compounds are octapeptides. This hormone\u2019s active form comes in 28- and 14-amino-acid varieties, and its analogues may be used to treat acromegaly. Cells that release this compound are selectively activated by ghrelin. This hormone, which is similar to cortistatin, is produced by delta cells. This hormone inhibits insulin and glucagon secretion. For 10 points, name this hormone that inhibits the activity of growth hormone.", "answer": "somatostatin [accept growth hormone-inhibiting hormone or GHIH before \u201cgrowth\u201d]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>somatostatin</u></b> [accept <b><u>growth hormone-inhibiting hormone</u></b> or <b><u>GHIH</u></b> before \u201cgrowth]", "acceptable": ["somatostatin", "somatostatin", "growth hormone-inhibiting hormone", "GHIH"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Four years after this man\u2019s most influential legislative achievement, issues regarding inspections were clarified in a law named for Ren\u00e9 Goblet (goh-blay), which also clearly defined a crucial distinction between \u201cpublic\u201d and \u201cprivate\u201d and made a brevet (breh-vay) a requirement for a certain profession. A speech by this man proclaiming that \u201cwoman must belong to science or she belongs to the Church\u201d was widely discussed in the public debate, nearly a decade later, over legislation named for Paul Bert (\"bare\"). This man\u2019s own legislative program led to a massive rise in the number of men in a profession that Charles P\u00e9guy called the \u201cblack hussars of the Republic.\u201d This man spearheaded the passage of legislation that amended the Falloux (fah-loo) Laws, which were passed in the 1850s and mandated an uneasy truce between the state and the church, to reflect his own stauch laicism and disdain for the clergy. For 10 points, what 19th-century French statesman\u2019s namesake 1881 and 1882 laws established mandatory, free, secular education?", "answer": "Jules Ferry [or Jules Fran\u00e7ois Camille Ferry; accept Jules Ferry laws]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Jules Ferry</u></b> [or <b><u>Jules Fran\u00e7ois Camille Ferry</u></b>; accept <b><u>Jules Ferry laws</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Jules Ferry", "Jules Ferry", "Jules Fran\u00e7ois Camille Ferry", "Jules Ferry laws"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A compound containing this element and oxygen is dissolved in DMSO in a reagent for the Swern-like Onodera oxidation. NMR based around this element tends to see chemical shifts between negative 180 to positive 250 ppm; additionally, due to inconsistent NOE in this element, integration is nearly useless. This element forms a four-membered ring with sulfur that decomposes into a pair of ylides (ILL-idz) used for thiation (\"thigh\"-AY-shun). This element and oxygen form a reagent with an adamantane structure that serves as a dessicant and whose name refers to its empirical formula. A reagent containing this element is used to alpha-brominate carboxylic acids. Like fluorine and hydrogen, this element exists nearly monoisotopically with a spin one-half nucleus. Lawesson\u2019s reagent contains sulfur and this element, which is bonded to three phenyls in a common ligand that reacts in the Wittig reaction. For 10 points, name this element found in the center of TPP, and below nitrogen on the periodic table.", "answer": "phosphorus [or P]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>phosphorus</u></b> [or <b><u>P</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["phosphorus", "phosphorus", "P"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}